Jiecheng Luo

PhD Student, Research Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, UCL **Postgraduate Teaching Assistant**, Global Business School for Health, UCL East <u>jiecheng.luo.20@ucl.ac.uk</u>

+44 07410 937710

I'm a self-motivated PhD student in Epidemiology and Public Health. My research interests revolve around social relationships and disability among older Chinese people. I have developed quantitative and analytical skills with a strong capacity to conduct independent research. I am interested in developing a career that combines teaching and research, while maintaining my interest in collaborating with people from multidisciplinary background.

Experiences

PGTA, Global Business School for Health UCL East (Sep 2022 - present)

- Modules: Leadership and Management in Global Healthcare (GBSH0010) and Changing Health Systems (GBSH0007).
- Hosting weekly seminars and marking on assessments.

PGTA, Research Department of Epidemiology and Public Health UCL (Jan 2022 - Jul 2022)

- Modules: Regression Modelling (IEHC0050), Health Inequalities over the Life Course (IEHC0049).
- Hosting online sessions on Zoom and marking on assessments.

Training Assistant, Information Services Division UCL (Sep 2021 - Nov 2023)

- Module: An Introduction to R with RStudio.
- Providing help to trainers and students during the session.

Field Researcher, Xiamen University (Jul 2019)

- Short-term survey on 'Monitoring Disease in Ningxia, One Rural Area of China'.
- Data collecting and analysis.

Public Relation Officer, Xiamen University (Sep 2018 - Aug 2019)

- Working at Postgraduate Student Union in School of Public Health.
- Managing public image and communication efforts.

Part-time Research Assistant, Xiamen University (Aug 2018 - Aug 2019)

- Project entitled 'Dynamic Changes in Heterogeneous Health Status among Older Chinese People and Their Healthcare Utilization'.
- Data cleaning, constructing statistical models, and visualizing.
- Interpreting results and drafting articles.

Teaching Assistant, Xiamen University (Jul 2018-Aug 2018)

- Module: Big Data Mining Technology in Health Care.
- Preparing materials, recording attendance, and marking on assessments.

Field Researcher, Xiamen University (Jul 2018 - Aug 2018)

- Project entitled 'Mild Cognitive Impairment among Old People in Xiamen City, China'.
- Conducting interviews and data recording.

Field Researcher, Anhui Medical University (Jul 2015 - Aug 2015)

- Project entitled 'Early Diagnosis and Early Treatment on Cancer in Urban Area of Anhui Province, China'.
- Conducting interviews and data recording.

Medical Intern, Chaohu Hospital of Anhui Medical University (Feb 2014 - Dec 2014)

• Practicing medicine in different specialties with guidance and supervision.

Educations

University College London (2020 - present, UK), PhD Student

- Enrolled in the PhD programme of Epidemiology and Public Health.
- Self-funded research project titled 'Association between social relationships and disability among older Chinese people', based on data from the China Health and Retirement Survey.
- Joint supervisors: Professor Anne McMunn and Dr Baowen Xue, Research Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, UCL.

Xiamen University (2017 - 2020, China), Master of Public Health

- Compulsory modules included: Advanced Health Statistics, Advanced Epidemiology, and Senior Health Service Management.
- Thesis entitled 'Heterogeneous health groups and healthcare utilization among older adults in China', based on data from the Chinese Longitudinal Healthy Longevity Survey.

Anhui Medical University (2012 - 2017, China), Bachelor of Management

- Major in Healthcare Management, with one-year medical training.
- Compulsory modules included: Social Medicine, Epidemiology, Health Statistics, Health Economics, Leadership Science, and Healthcare Management.

Skills

- Modelling and visualizing in R language.
- Communication and teamwork.
- English (advanced) and Mandarin Chinese (native).
- Photography.

Publications

- Ye L, Luo J, Shia B-C, Fang Y. Multidimensional Health Groups and Healthcare Utilization Among Elderly Chinese: Based on the 2014 CLHLS Dataset. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2019;16(20):3884. doi:10.3390/ijerph16203884
- Zeng Y, Luo J, Ou L, et al. The impact of medical insurance on medical expenses for older Chinese: Evidence from the national baseline survey of CLHLS. Medicine. 2019;98(39):e17302. doi:10.1097/MD.000000000017302
- Ye L, **Luo J**, Shia B-C, Fang Y. Heterogeneous health classes for older adults and their regional disparities in China: based on multidimensional health. Public Health. 2020;178:15-22. doi:10.1016/j.puhe.2019.08.023

Conferences

• The Aging & Public Health program of the American Public Health Association's 2019 Annual Meeting and Expo.

• The Gerontological Society of America's 71st Annual Scientific Meeting.

References

Professor Anne McMunn - University College London, a.mcmunn@ucl.ac.uk
Dr Baowen Xue - University College London, baowen.xue.10@ucl.ac.uk
Professor Ya Fang - Xiamen University, fangya@xmu.edu.cn